=Hot Blooded=
= مدوّنة حمراء =
=Episode 4=
= الحلقة 4 =
Who is it?
من هو؟
How did you get here?
كيف وصلت إلى هنا؟
I followed you.
تبعتك
Do you think the silver coins we gave you
هل تعتقد أن العملات الفضية التي أعطيناها لك
are not enough to show our sincerity?
لا تكفي لإظهار إخلاصنا؟
Your Royal Highness, you misunderstood.
صاحب السمو، لقد أسأت الفهم
I came
جئت
to thank you specially
شكرا خاصا لك
and also to bid farewell.
وكذلك الوداع
If I don't come,
إذا لم آت
I will die with everlasting regret.
سأموت مع الأسف الدائم
It was my son's mischief
كان سوء ابني
that made you and your daughter suffer.
الذي جعلك تعاني مع ابنتك
You should leave quickly.
يجب أن تغادر بسرعة
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
(Yang Tiexin)
(يانغ تييكسين)
Please do not touch it.
من فضلك لا تلمسه
This is my most precious possession.
هذه أثمن ما أملك
You should leave now.
يجب أن تغادر الآن
There was a pair
كان هناك زوج
of these iron spears.
من هذه الرمح الحديدية
Now
الآن
there is only one left.
لم يتبق سوى واحد فقط
The plow head is broken.
تم كسر قلعة الرأس
Tomorrow,
غدا
tell Zhang Mu from the East Village
تشانغ مو من القرية الشرقية
to fix it
لإصلاح الأمر
with a half catty of iron.
بنصف كاتير من الحديد
Xiruo,
شيرو يو
the plow head is broken
تم كسر الحنطة
Tomorrow, tell Zhang Mu from the East Village
غدا، أخبر تشانغ مو من القرية الشرقية
to fix it with a half catty of iron.
لإصلاحه بمقدار نصف كمية من الحديد
Who exactly are you?
من أنت بالضبط؟
How do you know what my husband said
كيف هل تعرف ما قاله زوجي
the night he died?
الليلة التي مات فيها؟
Tiexin?
تييكسين؟
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
You are Tiexin?
أنت تيexين؟
Tiexin!
تييكسين!
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
Take me away.
خذني بعيدا
Take me to the underworld.
خذني إلى العالم الخلفي
I want to be a ghost with you.
أريد أن أكون شبح معك
If it weren't for the child,
لولا الطفل
I would have come to find you long ago.
كنت سآتي إليك منذ فترة طويلة
Do I look like
هل أبدو كأنني
a ghost to you?
كشبح لك؟
How did you survive?
كيف نجوت؟
Mom.
أمي
It's going to snow.
انها سوف تساعد على الثلج
Is it cold in the room?
هل هو بارد في الغرفة؟
Let me help you make a fire.
دعيني أساعدك على إطلاق النار
It's not cold.
هذا ليس بارد
It's very warm
الجو حار جدًا
inside the house.
داخل المنزل
Is it warm enough?
هل هو دافئ بما فيه الكفاية؟
It's been frosty and rainy.
إنه جمد ومطر
You must feel cold.
لا بد أن تشعر بالبرد
Mom.
أمي
Who are you talking to?
إلى من تتحدثين؟
I'm already in the bed.
أنا داخل السرير بالفعل
Aren't you in the bed?
أليس السرير؟
Why are you staring at the cabinet in a daze?
لماذا تحدق بالمجلس في تجرؤ؟
I'm going to bed now.
سأخلد إلى النوم الآن
Kang.
كانغ
You should rest early too.
يجب أن ترتاح مبكرا أيضا
Mom.
أمي
Are you keeping something from me?
هل تخفي شيئًا عني
No, not at all.
لا، على الإطلاق
Am I your real son?
هل أنا ابنك الحقيقي؟
Of course you are.
بالطبع أنت كذلك
Then why are you always...
إذًا لماذا أنت دائمًا...
Why do you
لماذا أنت
always hide things from me?
تخفي الأشياء عني دائمًا؟
Just like...
بنفس القدر...
Kang, stop it!
كانغ، توقفي!
He is your
إنه أنت
biological father.
والدك البيولوجي
How is that possible?
كيف يمكن ذلك؟
Mom.
أمي
You must be crazy.
يجب أن تكوني مجنونة
My father is Prince Zhao of the Jin Empire.
والدي هو الأمير تشاو من إمبراطورية جين
How could he be my dad?
كيف يمكن أن يكون أبي؟
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدثين؟
I'm telling the truth.
أنا أقول الحقيقة
You're not from the Jin Empire.
أنت لست من إمبراطورية جين
You're one of the Hans.
أنت واحد من عائلة هان
Your name is not Wanyan Kang.
اسمك ليس وانيان كانغ
Your real surname is Yang.
لقبك الحقيقي هو يانغ
Your name
اسمك
should be Yang Kang.
لا بد أن يانغ كانغ
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدثين؟
It's absolutely true.
هذا صحيح تمامًا
I'm telling you now
سأقول لك الآن
word by word.
كلمة بكلمة
Your biological father is him.
والدك البيولوجي هو
His name is Yang Tiexin.
اسمه يانغ تيهشين
I want to find my father.
أريد أن أجد والدي
I want my father to talk to you.
أريد أن أتحدث إليك يا أبي
Kang.
كانغ
Your father is here.
والدك هنا
Son.
ابن
Take a look.
ألق نظرة
What words are carved on this spear?
ما هي الكلمات المحقونة على هذه الرمح؟
Yang
يانغ
Tiexin.
تييكسين
(Yang Tiexin) Your biological father
(يانغ تيكين) والدك البيولوجي
used to use this iron spear a lot.
استخدم هذا رمح الحديد كثيرًا
His name is carved on it.
تم كتابة اسمه عليه
Tiexin.
تيكسين
No.
لا
This guy's surname is Mu.
لقب هذا الرجل هو مو
His daughter is Mu Nianci.
ابنته مو نيانتسي
Mom.
أمي
You must have been deceived.
لا بد أنك خدعت
How could he deceive me?
كيف يمكنه أن يخدعني؟
Come and see for yourself.
تعالي لرؤية بنفسك
Don't you always ask me
ألا تسألني دائمًا
where did this iron plow come from?
من أين أتت هذه الحيلة الحديدية؟
And these tables and stools.
وهذه الطاولات والموهرات
All the furnishings inside this room
جميع الأثاث داخل هذه الغرفة
were transported
تم نقلها
all the way from Niujia Village
على طول الطريق من قرية نيوجيا
to here.
إلى هنا
Every piece of furnishings
كل قطعة من الأثاث
in this room
في هذه غرفة
is something that your biological father
هو شيء استخدمه والدك البيولوجي
and I used to use.
وأنا التي استخدمتها
What's so good about all this crap?
ما الجيد في كل هذه الملابس؟
Everything in the palace
كل شيء في القصر
is better than them.
أفضل منهم
But in my eyes,
ولكن في نظري
these old things
هذه الأشياء القديمة
are much better
أفضل بكثير
than the fine furniture in the palace,
من الأثاث الفاخر في القصر
my child.
طفلتي
You really have no luck.
ليس لديك حظا حقا
You didn't grow up
لم تكبر
with your biological father
مع والدك البيولوجي
in a shabby place surrounded by these things.
في مكان محاط بهذه الأشياء
Isn't that my blessing?
أليس هذا نعمة لي؟
Mom.
أمي
You're being unreasonable.
أنت غير معقولة
He can't be my father.
لا يمكن أن يكون والدي
He's a spy who broke into the palace.
إنه جاسوس اقتحم القصر
I have to kill him.
يجب أن أقتله
Mom.
أمي
I'll kill him for you now.
سأقتله من أجلك الآن
Kang!
كانغ!
If you act recklessly like this,
إذا تصرفت بتهور هكذا
I will have to
سأضطر إلى
die in front of you.
أن أموت أمامك
- Mother! - Xiruo!
- أمي! - زيرو!
Xiruo!
شيراو!
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
Why did you do this to yourself?
لماذا فعلت هذا بنفسك؟
Let go of my mother!
دع أمي تذهب!
Let my mother go!
دعني أمي تذهب!
Only sons in the Yang family
فقط الفتيات في عائلة يانغ
can learn this move.
يمكن تعلم هذه الخطوة
I believe your master did not teach you this.
أعتقد أن معلمك لم يعلمك هذه
Dad.
أبي
Daughter.
ابنتي
Nianci.
نيانسي
This is my wife
هذه زوجتي
that I told you about
إنني قلت لك
countless times.
مرات لا حصر لها
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
This is my adopted daughter,
هذه هي ابنتي المعتمدة
Mu Nianci.
مو نيانتسي
Mom?
أمي؟
My child.
طفلتي
Let's go.
لنذهب
Rong.
رونغ
I finally found you!
وجدتك أخيرا!
Jing.
جينغ
Follow me.
اتبعوني
They are over here.
إنهم هنا
Quick.
هيا
Go get them.
اذهب للحصول عليها
Go.
اذهبي
Don't let them escape.
لا تدعهم يهربون
What should we do?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل؟
Jing.
جينغ
It's a dry well.
إنه بئر جاف
Quick.
سريع
Go take a look over there.
اذهب وألق نظرة هناك
- Let's hide in here. - Okay.
- دعنا نختبئ هنا - حسنا
Jing.
جينغ
Rong.
رونغ
Who is there?
من هناك؟
Rong, run!
رونغ، اركض!
I remember your voice.
أتذكر صوتك
You are the apprentice of the Seven Freaks of Jiangnan.
أنت تلميذة من مقاطعات جيانغنان السبعة
It's a pity that I didn't
من المؤسف أنني لم أتخلص منك
get rid of you last time.
التخلص منك المرة الماضية
Since you came to meet your doom,
بما أنك أتيت لتحقيق أمنيتك
I will grant your wish.
سأعطي أمنيتك
Mei Ruohua.
مي روههوا
How do you know my real name?
كيف تعرف اسمي الحقيقي؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Swing the sword admist peach blossoms,
أعيريني أزهار خوخ الناظر
playing the song on a jade flute.
الذي يعزف عن الأغنية على تدفق اليشم
My last name is Huang.
اسمي الأخير هو هوانغ
You are...
أنت...
The Tanzhi Peak, Qingyin Cave,
غريب التنزاني، كهف تشينجين
Green Bamboo Grove,
وأخضر بامبو غروف
and Sword Trial Pavilion on the Peach Blossom Island.
وجناح محاكمات سيف على جزيرة بوسوم الخوخ
Do you still remember them?
هل ما زلت تتذكرهم؟
Master?
معلمي؟
Good.
جيد
You haven't forgot my father.
أنت لم تنسى والدي
The old man
الرجل القديم
still hasn't forgotten about you.
لم ينس أمرك بعد
He
جاء
came to see you in person.
جاء لرؤيتك شخصيا
Master is here?
المعلم هنا؟
Don't try to fool me.
لا تحاول خداعي
So you've gone too far in your practice
لذلك ذهبت بعيدا في تدريبك
and can't walk.
ولا يمكنك المشي
Jing.
جينغ
Fallen Petals Sword Palm.
أصيب بطلق ناري من البيتلز
Not bad.
لا بأس
This move is called Flying Flowers in Jiangcheng.
هذه الخطوة تسمى أزهار طيفية في جيانغتشينغ
My father taught you that.
لقد علمك والدي ذلك
You didn't forget, did you?
أنت لم تنس، أليس كذلك؟
Huang,
هوانغ
where is my master?
أين معلمي؟
Senior Mei,
أيتها المشرفة مي
now you have a chance to make amends for your mistakes.
الآن لديك فرصة للتعويض عن أخطائك
What chance?
أي فرصة؟
Some people are bullying me.
بعض الناس يتنمر عليّ
You drive them away.
أنت تدفعهم بعيدا
My father always listens to me.
والدي يصغي لي دائما
When my father arrives,
عندما يصل والدي
I will plead for you.
سأطلب منكم
I will be at your service.
سأكون في خدمتك
You thief!
أنت لص!
Nine Yin Skeleton Claw?
تسعة ين سكلتون من القانون؟
And you say you have no relationship
تقول إنك لا علاقة لك
with the Twin Killers in the Dark Wind.
مع مرعي التون في الرياح المظلمة
Your master is clearly Mei Chaofeng.
معلمك هو لي تشاوفنغ بوضوح
My master?
معلمي؟
Let her practice for another hundred years
دعها تتدرب لمدة مائة عام أخرى
and see if she'll be qualified.
لمعرفة ما إذا كانت ستكون مؤهلة
Do you think I am qualified?
هل تعتقدين أنني مؤهل؟
Senior Mei.
أيتها الرئيسة مي
It was this villain
كان هذا الأشرار
who tried to bully me.
الذي حاول التنمر علي
Huang.
هوانغ
You were just trying to trick me, right?
كنت تحاول فقط خدقتي، أليس كذلك؟
If Master is really nearby,
إذا كان المعلم في مكان قريب حقا
these people wouldn't dare to be so arrogant.
هؤلاء الناس لن يجرؤون على التعجرف كثيرا
Senior Mei.
أيتها المشرفة مي
What do you mean by this?
ماذا تقصدين بهذا؟
Tell me the mental cultivation methods of Peach Blossom Island,
أخبرني بطرق الزراعة العقلية في جزيرة برسوم الخوخ
and I will naturally help you vent your anger.
وسأساعدك بشكل طبيعي في تهدئة غضبك
Okay.
حسنًا
Sit cross-legged,
اجلس متقاطعًا
point five centers to the sky.
أبرزن خمسة مراكز إلى السماء
Five centers?
خمسة مراكز؟
The center of your palms,
مركز قصرك
your feet,
قدميك
and your head.
ورأسك
Those are the five centers.
هذه هي المراكز الخمسة
Rong.
رونغ
The martial arts of Peach Blossom Island
فنون الدفاع عن النفس في جزيرة زهر الخوخ
aren't fun.
لست ممتعا
You should ask me to be your master
يجب أن تطلب مني أن أكون سيدك
and come to the Mount White Camel with me.
والمواظبة على جبل الكاميرون الأبيض معي
How dare you insult the Peach Blossom Island.
كيف تجرؤ على إهانة جزيرة زهر الخوخ
- I should kill you. - How bold!
- يجب أن أقتلك - كم هي جريئة!
This woman is very powerful.
هذه المرأة قوية جدا
Be careful, everyone.
كوني حذرة جميعًا
However powerful she is,
مهما كانت قوية
she's blind.
إنها أعمى
I don't know if the Copper Corpse is here.
لا أعرف إن كان كوربس النحاس هنا
Let's not worry about it for now.
دعنا لا نقلق بهذا الشأن في الوقت الحالي
Find a way to kill her first.
ابحثي عن طريقة لقتلها أولًا
Let's do it together.
دعونا نفعل ذلك معا
This way!
هذا الطريق!
I'm already lucky enough
أنا محظوظ بما فيه الكفاية
to have reunited with my wife today.
للبقاء مع زوجتي اليوم
Even if I have to die now,
حتى لو كان عليّ أن أموت الآن
I am satisfied.
أنا سعيد
Don't talk nonsense, Tiexin.
لا تتحدثي هراء يا تيكسين
I'll stay with you even if I die.
سأبقى معك حتى لو مت
Child,
طفل
run for your life.
اهرع لحياتك
No, I want to be with you.
لا، أريد أن أكون معك
Fine.
حسنا
Having a wife
الحصول على زوجة
and a daughter like this,
وابنة كهذه
what more could I ask for?
ما الذي يمكن أن أطلب منه أكثر من ذلك؟
Guard the city gate
حراسة بوابة المدينة
and bring back the Princess.
وإعادة الأميرة
Kang!
كانغ!
Are you really going to
هل ستجعل والدك البيولوجي
make your own biological father die?
ستجعل والدك البيولوجي يموت؟
That thief has bewitched the Princess.
ذلك اللص حرك الأميرة
The reward for killing him
المكافأة على قتله
is one hundred taels.
هو مائة تايل
Take care of your mother.
اعتني بأمك
This way!
هذا الطريق!
Kang.
كانغ
I'm Yang Tiexin.
أنا يانغ تيهشين
May I have your name?
هل لي باسمك؟
Thank God!
شكرًا الله!
You're still alive.
أنت لا تزال على قيد الحياة
I am Ma Yu from the Quanzhen School.
أنا ما يو من مدرسة كوانزين
Master Qiu Chuji and I
السيد تشوجي وأنا
are close friends.
نحن أصدقاء مقربون
Please help me get away.
يرجى مساعدتي في الابتعاد
Yang.
يانغ
I will take you out of the city now.
سأخرجك من المدينة الآن
Kang.
كانغ
This person is the head of the Quanzhen School.
هذا الشخص هو مدير مدرسة كوانجين
Usual soldiers can't deal with him.
الجنود الاعتياديون لا يستطيعون التعامل معه
Go to the palace
اذهبي إلى القصر
to invite some masters to help.
لدعوة بعض السيدات للمساعدة
Yes, Father.
نعم يا أبي
- Dad. - Daughter.
- أبي - ابنتي - هيا
- Let's go. - This way.
- هيا بنا - هذا الطريق
Make sure to get
احرصي على الحصول على
the Princess back.
تراجع الأميرة
Yes.
نعم
This woman's legs are paralyzed.
ساقي هذه المرأة مشلولة
She's depending on the kid in the back.
إنها تعتمد على الطفل في الخلف
That's her weakness.
هذه نقطة ضعفها
Kill him first.
اقتله أولًا
- Rong. - Everyone, please stop.
- رونغ - الجميع، توقف أرجوكم
We're all on the same side.
نحن جميعًا على نفس الجانب
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
We are all martial arts practitioners.
نحن جميعا ممارسون فنون الدفاع عن النفس
We should settle scores according to the rules of the martial world.
يجب أن نقسم الحسابات وفقا لقواعد عالم القتال
Please stay out of this, Your Highness.
أرجوك لا تتدخلي في الأمر يا صاحب السمو
My mother has been kidnapped by a villain.
لقد تم اختطاف أمي من قبل شرير
The situation is urgent on my father's side.
الوضع عاجل إلى جانب والدي
Are you all going to stand by and do nothing?
هل ستقفون جميعا جانبا ولا تفعلون شيئا؟
Prince Zhao made a generous offer to invite me to come.
قدم الأمير تشاو عرضا سخيا لدعوتي إلى الحضور
Now there is trouble in the palace,
الآن هناك مشكلة في القصر
how can we just sit back?
كيف لنا أن نجلس فقط؟
The Princess has been kidnapped.
تم اختطاف الأميرة
If we don't go to help,
إذا لم نذهب للمساعدة
it will be difficult to establish a foothold in the palace in the future.
سيكون من الصعب إنشاء موطئ قدم في القصر في المستقبل
Witch.
ساقطة
I'll make a note of this.
سأشير إلى هذا
Lead the way, Your Highness.
هذا الطريق يا صاحب السمو
Let's save the Princess first.
دعنا ننقذ الأميرة أولا
Go.
هيا
Senior Mei.
كبير مي
Second master.
المعلم الثاني
Masters.
سادة
Masters, don't chase after them.
سادة، لا تلاحقهم
Jing.
جينغ
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلين؟
Why are you together with that witch?
لماذا أنت مع تلك الساحرة؟
She just saved me.
لقد أنقذتني للتو
Master Wang Chuyi
سيد وانغ تشويي
was poisoned.
كان مسموما
I came here to find the antidote.
جئت إلى هنا لأجد الترياق
But there were some villains
لكن كان هناك بعض الأشرار
trying to kill me.
يحاولون قتلي
Then I encountered Mei Chaofeng.
ثم قابلت مي تشاوفنغ
She drove away those villains
أقلعت هؤلاء الأشرار
and saved me.
وأنقذتني
What nonsense are you talking about?
عن أي هراء تتحدث؟
We searched everywhere for her but couldn't find her.
بحثنا عنها في كل مكان لكننا لم نتمكن من العثور عليها
Today we finally met her.
اليوم التقينا بها أخيرًا
Can't let her escape.
لا يمكن أن تدعها تهرب
Forget it.
انس الأمر
Jing won't lie.
جينغ لن يكذب
Since she saved Jing once,
بما أنها أنقذت جينغ مرة واحدة
we should be grateful
سنكون ممتنين
and let her off this time.
ودعها تذهب هذه المرة
Consider it as repaying her favor.
اعتبر أنه سداد فضلها
This makes sense.
هذا منطقي
Moreover, when we fought with her,
علاوة على ذلك، عندما تشاجرنا معها
she was already seriously injured,
كانت قد أصيبت بجروح خطيرة بالفعل
If we kill her now,
إذا قتلناها الآن
people will say
سيقول الناس
we took advantage of her vulnerability.
نستفيد من ضعفها
That's right.
هذا صحيح
So be it.
فليكن ذلك
Next time I see her,
عندما أراها في المرة القادمة
I will definitely kill her.
لن أقتلها بالتأكيد
You're awake.
أنت استيقظت
Thanks a lot to your help.
شكرا جزيلا لمساعدتك
Don't thank me.
لا تشكريني
You helped me once.
ساعدتني ذات مرة
And I helped you.
وأنا ساعدتك
Let's call it even.
حتى نسميها
I'm also afraid that my father will know
أخشى أيضا أن والدي سيعرف
I let someone from the Peach Blossom Island
قد تركت شخصا من جزيرة بوسوم الخوخ
die at the hands of others.
أن يموت على أيدي الآخرين
He'll blame me in the future.
سوف يلوم علي في المستقبل
So my master
لذلك معلمي
didn't come.
لم يأت
That's right.
هذا صحيح
How could he deliberately
كيف يمكنه أن يأتي رؤيتي عمدا
come to see me, a traitor?
رؤيتي، خائن؟
Do you really want to see him?
هل تريد رؤيته حقًا؟
Aren't you afraid he will kill you?
ألست خائفا من أنه سيقتلك؟
I am afraid.
أنا خائفة
But I still want to see him.
لكنني ما زلت أريد أن أراه
No matter how he punishes me,
بغض النظر عن الطريقة التي يعاقب بها علي
I am willing to accept it.
أنا على استعداد لقبوله
I used to
كنت
hear my father mention
أن أسمع والدي يذكر
you ungrateful disciples.
أنت تلاميذ غير ممتنين
So
لذلك
this time I passed on the mental cultivation methods
هذه المرة مررت على أساليب الزراعة العقلية
because I pitied you for him.
لأنني أشفق عليك
Otherwise, if you continue to cultivate like this,
وإلا، إذا واصلت الزراعة هكذا
the paralysis of both legs is just the beginning.
شلل كلا الساقين هو مجرد بداية
You will definitely die in the future.
بالتأكيد ستموتين في المستقبل
Thank you then.
شكرًا لك إذن
By the way, why did you come to the palace?
بالمناسبة، لماذا جئت إلى القصر؟
Tell me about it.
أخبرني عن ذلك
That day,
في ذلك اليوم
after the battle with the Seven Freaks of Jiangnan,
بعد المعركة مع مقاطعات جيانغنان السبع
I was shot blind by Ke Zhen'e.
أطلق الكي تشنأ النار عليّ
Xuanfeng was killed by the Seven Freaks.
قتل شوانفنغ على يد الحوش السبعة
To avoid the Seven Freaks,
لتجنب المقاطعات السبع
I hid in the Sixth Prince's palace.
اختبأت في قصر الأمير السادس
They thought I was only
اعتقدوا أنني فقط
a pitiful blind woman,
امرأة أعمى مشفقة
so they arrange for me to work in a
لذلك يرتب لي أن أعمل في مبنى
deserted backyard.
فناء الخلفي مهجور
I secretly practiced martial arts at night.
مارست سرا فنون الدفاع عن النفس في الليل
No one noticed it
لم يلاحظ أحد
in the first couple of months.
في الشهرين الأولين
Until one day,
حتى يوم واحد
he caught me practicing.
أمسك بي وهي تتدرب
Who is there?
من هناك؟
I never expected
لم أتوقع أبدا
that in the palace,
أنه في القصر
(Young Wanyan Kang) there's a remarkable expert
(أيها الشاب وانيان كانغ) هناك خبير رائع
hidden in here.
مختبئا هنا
Your Highness.
سموك
Rest assured.
كن مطمئنا
I know you don't want
أعلم أنك لا تريد
others to know about your martial arts skills.
أن يعرف الآخرون عن مهاراتك في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
I will never tell anyone.
لن أخبر أي شخص أبدا
I have thought of
لقد فكرت في
a more discreet location.
موقع أكثر حذرا
No one
لا أحد
will disturb your practice here.
سوف يزعج تدريبك هنا
Your Highness.
سموك
Why are you helping me like this?
لماذا تساعدني هكذا؟
I want to be your disciple
أريد أن أكون تلميذك
to learn martial arts.
لتعلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس
I should have killed him,
كان يجب أن أقتله
but he has a noble identity.
لكن لديه هوية نبيلة
Harming him will bring big trouble.
وجبره سيجلب مشكلة كبيرة
Furthermore,
علاوة على ذلك
I am grateful that his father saved me.
أنا ممتن لأن والده أنقذني
So I agreed to teach him.
لذلك وافقت على أن أعلمه
So
لذلك
I stayed in the palace.
بقيت في القصر
Quick.
هيا
This way!
هذا الطريق!
- Xiruo. - Mother!
- شيرو هو - أمي!
- How is it? - How are you?
- كيف حالها؟ - كيف حالك؟
It's hard to get away
من الصعب الابتعاد
taking all of us.
بأخذنا جميعا
I feel
أشعر
really bad about it.
الأمر سيء للغاية
Don't say that, Yang.
لا تقل ذلك يا يانغ
Let's first find our way
دعنا نجد طريقنا
down the mountain.
حتى أسفل الجبل
Mr. Ma.
السيد ما
If we go down the mountain like this,
إذا انزلنا الجبل هكذا
we'll inevitably encounter pursuers.
سنواجه بالتأكيد مسابقات
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I have already left marks
لقد تركت بالفعل علامات
of our Quanzhen School along the way.
من مدرسة كوانجين لدينا على طول الطريق
My two junior martial brothers,
إخوتي الأصغر
Qiu Chuji and Wang Chuyi,
تشيو تشجي وانغ تشوي
are both nearby.
كلاهما قريبان
Once they see them,
بمجرد رؤيتهما
they will come to help us.
سوف يأتون لمساعدتنا
Master Qiu will come?
سيأتي السيد تشي يو؟
With the support of the two of them,
بدعم من الاثنين
those Jin soldiers
هؤلاء الجنود جين
can't stop us.
لا يمكنهم إيقافنا
- Good. - Let's go.
- جيد - هيا بنا
Over there.
هناك
- Don't let him run away. - This way.
- لا تدعه يهرب - هذا الطريق - بهذا الطريق
Quick.
سريع
- Oh no.
- هذا الطريق - لا
I'll fight them!
سأحاربهم!
Yang.
يانغ
I'll stop them.
سأقوم بإيقافهم
You guys go quickly.
اذهبا بسرعة
Dad, protect Mom.
أبي، أحمي أمي
Come back.
عد
Quick.
هيا
Not one can get away.
لا يمكن لأحد أن يهرب
I'm going to kill that villain.
سأقتل ذلك الشريرة
Dad.
أبي
Kang, stop it!
كانغ، توقف!
Yang.
يانغ
I finally found you!
وجدتك أخيرا!
Master Qiu.
سيد تشي يو
It's been eighteen years since we parted ways in Niujia Village.
مضى ثمانية عشر عاما منذ أن افترقنا في قرية نيوجيا
It feels like a lifetime ago.
أشعر وكأنه منذ فترة طويلة
Master, it's me.
معلمي، هذه أنا
I never had a disciple like you
لم يكن لدي تلميذ مثلك
who took a villain as a father.
الذي اتخذ شرير كأب
Are you going to kill me?
هل ستقتلني؟
Master, be careful.
معلمي، كن حذرا
Stop it!
توقف!
Sure enough, you are the young prince.
بالتأكيد، أنت الأمير الشاب
Qiu Chuji.
تشوجي
You were hit by the bone-piercing nail.
لقد ضربتك أظافر العمامة
You don't have much time left.
لم يبق لديك الكثير من الوقت
Master, I didn't mean it.
معلمي، أنا لم أقصد ذلك
Good disciple.
تلميذة جيدة
Junior.
ابدأ
Use your internal energy to detoxify.
استخدمي طاقتك الداخلية لإزالة السموم
- I will protect you. - Okay.
- سأحميك - حسنًا
Master, I'm here to help you.
معلمي، أنا هنا لمساعدتك
Tiexin!
تيخين!
If you want to kill him,
إذا كنت تريد قتله
you have to kill me first.
يجب أن تقتلني أولا
Stop.
توقف
Do not hurt the Princess.
لا تؤذي الأميرة
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
Come back with me.
عد معي
I will not go back with you.
لن أعود معك
Mom.
أمي
Why are you still protecting that villain?
لماذا ما زلت تحمي ذلك الشريرة؟
Come back quickly.
عودي بسرعة
Father will forgive you.
سوف يغفر لك الأب
I'm not going back.
لن أعود
My husband is still alive.
زوجي لا يزال على قيد الحياة
I will stay with him forever.
سأبقى معه إلى الأبد
If he goes to the ends of the earth,
إذا ذهب إلى نهاية الأرض
I'll follow him.
سأتبعه
Mom.
أمي
If you go with him,
إذا ذهبت معه
what should I do?
ماذا يجب أن أفعل؟
Don't you want me anymore?
ألم تعد تريدني؟
Don't you want our family anymore?
ألا تريدين عائلتنا بعد الآن؟
You traitor.
أنت خائن
You've taken the enemy as your father
لقد اتخذت العدو كوالدك
for eighteen years.
لمدة ثمانية عشر عاما
Now your biological father is here,
الآن والدك البيولوجي هنا
don't you want to recognize him?
ألا تريد التعرف عليه؟
Master.
معلمي
My father is Wanyan Honglie,
والدي هو وانيان هونغليه
my name is Wanyan Kang.
اسمي وانيان كانغ
He raised me.
لقد ربّني
These eighteen years of affection
هذه السنوات الثماني عشرة من العاطفة
cannot be replaced by anyone.
لا يمكن الاستعاضة عنها بأي شخص
I have only
لقد
met this person twice.
قابلت هذا الشخص مرتين
Why should I acknowledge him?
لماذا يجب أن أعترف به؟
Child,
طفل
it's not your fault.
هذا ليس خطأك
After all, you were born
بعد كل شيء، لقد وُلدت
in this palace.
في هذا القصر
But back then,
ولكن في ذلك الوقت
I entered the palace
دخلت القصر
for you.
نيابة عنك
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
Are you telling the truth?
هل تقول الحقيقة؟
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات
you've never treated me as your husband,
لم تعاملني أبدا كزوجك
or this place
أو هذا المكان
as your own home?
كمنزلك؟
In the past eighteen years,
في السنوات الثماني عشرة الماضية
although everyone calls me princess
على الرغم من أن الجميع يدعوني أميرة
in the palace,
في القصر
in my heart, I know
في قلبي، أعرف
I have long been married to the Yang family.
لقد تزوجت لفترة طويلة من عائلة يانغ
I live and die with him.
أنا أعيش وأموت معه
I am not worthy of you, Your Royal Highness.
أنا لا أستحق منك يا صاحب السمو الملكي
I don't care.
لا يهمني
I only care about you.
أنا أهتم لأمرك فقط
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات
you have always been
لقد كنت دائما
thinking about the past,
بالتفكير في الماضي
and I have been trying
ولقد كنت أحاول
to find ways
لإيجاد طرق
to help you forget the past.
لمساعدتك على نسيان الماضي
For you,
بالنسبة لك
I am willing to give up everything,
أنا على استعداد للتخلي عن كل شيء
even if I have to
حتى لو كان علي أن
abandon the throne.
التخلي عن العرش
Look at the court officials,
انظروا إلى مسؤولي المحكمة
everyone has wives and concubines.
الجميع لديهم زوجات أو محظيات
But you alone
لكنك وحدك
are enough for me.
كافية بالنسبة لي
Your Royal Highness,
صاحب السمو الملكي
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
I don't want you to say sorry!
لا أريدك أن تعرب عن الأسف!
I want you to tell me,
أريدك أن تخبرني
have you not had
ألم يكن لديك
any feelings for me
أي مشاعر لي
over these years?
على مدى هذه السنوات؟
I used to think
كنت أفكر
my husband had passed away,
أن زوجي توفي
so I intended to spend the rest of my life
لذلك كنت أعتزم قضاء بقية حياتي
serving you
بالخدمة عليك
and repaying your kindness.
لرد لطفك
But now
ولكن الآن
my husband is still alive.
زوجي لا يزال على قيد الحياة
I can no longer accept
لا يمكنني أن أقبل
your affection anymore.
شغوفك بعد الآن
Xiruo.
شيرو يو
I've loved you dearly
لقد أحبتك كثيرا
for eighteen years.
لمدة ثمانية عشر عاما
Unexpectedly,
على غير المتوقع
those years were wasted after all.
تلك السنوات تم إهدارها في النهاية
Your Royal Highness,
صاحب السمو الملكي
I have never asked anything of you.
لم أسأل أي شيء منك
But today I want to beg you
ولكن اليوم أريد أن أتوسل إليك
to let me and Tiexin go.
لتدعني وتييكسين يذهبان
Don't beg him!
لا تتوسل إليه!
Impossible.
مستحيل
Even if I can't
حتى لو لم أستطع
get your love in my life,
الحصول على حبك في حياتي
I won't let him get what he wants.
لن أسمح له بالحصول على ما يريد
Whoever dares to stop me
من يجرؤ على إيقافي
from welcoming back the Princess
من الترحيب بعودة الأميرة
will be killed!
سوف تُقتل!
Father.
أبي
Junior.
صباح الخير
Things have come to this.
لقد وصلت الأمور إلى هذا الحد
I'm afraid there is no escape.
أخشى ألا يكون هناك هروب
So what?
ما الأمر؟
The followers of Quanzhen School
أتباع مدرسة كانزين
aren't afraid of death.
لا يخافون من الموت
Wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة
Everything today started
بدأ كل شيء اليوم
because of me.
بسببي
I don't want to bring trouble to anyone.
لا أريد إثارة المتاعب لأي أحد
Wanyan Honglie.
وانيان هونغليه
If you were a man,
إذا كنت رجلا
don't involve the innocent people.
لا تشرك الأبرياء
Today,
اليوم
I will
سأعطيك
give you an explanation.
أعطيك تفسيرا
- Yang! - Don't!
- يانغ! - لا تفعل!
- Dad!
- أبي!
- Tiexin!
- تيخين!
Tiexin!
تيكين!
Dad!
أبي!
Xiruo.
شيرو هو
- Come back with me. - Don't come over.
- عد معي - لا تأتي -
Dad.
أبي
Your Royal Highness,
صاحب السمو
you saved my life.
لقد أنقذت حياتي
Today,
اليوم
I'm returning it to you.
أنا أعود إليك
We are even in this lifetime.
نحن حتى في هذا العمر
Don't!
لا تفعلي!
- Mother! - Xiruo!
- أمي! - شيرو!
Mother!
أمي!
♪I wander in the martial world♪
♪ أتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪I drink a thousand cups of wine and sing to the sky♪
♪ أشرب ألف كوب من النبيذ والغناء إلى السماء ♪
♪Life and death intertwined♪
♪ الحياة والموت متشابكين ♪
♪Leaning against the railing and shouting♪
♪ الوقوف ضد الغرق والنار ♪
♪Stars and moon over the wild expanse♪
♪ النجوم والقمر فوق التوسع البري ♪
♪Longbows shooting toward the distant sun♪
♪ أصوات طويلة تطلق نحو الشمس البعيدة ♪
♪We meet in mountains and rivers♪
♪ نلتقي في الجبال والأنهار ♪
♪Rushing through narrow paths♪
♪ التحرك عبر مسارات ضيقة ♪
♪I wander through the martial world♪
♪ تتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪All glitz mere illusions♪
♪ كل ألفاظ بسيطة ♪
♪Cutting off all debts♪
♪ إلغاء جميع الديون ♪
♪Only the shadows of swords and gleaming blades can be seen♪
♪ فقط ظلال السيوف والشفرات الكاذبة يمكن رؤيتها ♪
♪Fearless, undaunted♪
♪ لا خوف ولا مهرب ♪
♪The marial world is a lifetime of daring♪
♪ العالم الملكي هو حياة من الجرأة ♪
♪Who knows my dreams and ambitions♪
♪ من يعرف أحلامي وطموحاتي ♪
♪Wakening to find them as distant dreams♪
♪ الاستيقاظ للعثور عليهم كأحلام بعيدة ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع ودقيق ♪
♪Thousands of dreams span ages♪
♪ بآلاف الأحلام تمتد عبر الأعمار ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Ask the youth what it means♪
♪ اطلب من الشباب ما يعنيه ♪
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪True to their hearts♪
♪ أرغب في قلوبهم ♪
♪Or lost in the dust♪
♪ أو خسر في الغبار ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع وغالي ♪
♪People in the world varied and numerous♪
♪ الناس في العالم متنوعون وعديدون ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Who truly understands♪
♪ من يفهم ♪ حقا
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪Searching to truly grasp♪
♪ ابحث عن فهم ♪ حقا
♪Only then do they discern♪
♪ إذن لا يتلاحظوا ♪
♪Achievements and mistakes are transient♪
♪ الإنجازات والأخطاء عابرة ♪
♪To the end, yet steps persist♪
♪ حتى النهاية، لكن الخطوات لا تزال مستمرة ♪
♪We can feel pain and also joy♪
♪ يمكننا أن نشعر بالألم والسعادة ♪
♪We can charge forward or retreat♪
♪ يمكننا أن نتراجع للأمام ♪
♪No need to look back♪
♪ لا داعي للنظر إلى الوراء ♪
♪Rush through wind and clouds, shake the universe♪
♪ مرور الرياح والسحب، تهز الكون ♪
♪No matter the journey's length♪
♪ لا يهم طول الرحلة ♪
♪Entering the martial world♪
♪ دخول عالم القتال ♪
♪I fear not the endless journey♪
♪ لا أخشى الرحلة التي لا نهاية لها ♪